Finding Aid for the Josiah Royce Memorial Collection, 1875-1936
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Josiah Royce Memorial Collection,
1875-1936
253
20 boxes (10 linear ft.)
Josiah Royce (1855-1916) was a professor of philosophy at the University of California at Berkeley and Harvard University. His published works include: Primer of Logical Analysis for the Use of Composition Students (1881), The Religious Aspect of Philosophy (1885) and The Spirit of Modern Philosophy (1892). The collection consists of writings by and about Josiah Royce, copies of his correspondence, books, clippings and photographs.
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Department of Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Collection was originally assembled by UCLA Department of Philosophy. Transferred from Royce Hall, 1954.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 4233228
Biography/History
Royce was born on November 20, 1855 in Grass Valley, California; AB, University of California at Berkeley, 1875; studied at Leipzig and Göttingen Universities (1875-76), and then entered Johns Hopkins University, where he received his Ph.D in 1878; instructor in English literature and logic (1878-82), University of California at Berkeley; instructor in philosophy (1882-85), assistant professor (1885-92), professor of the history of philosophy (1892-1914), and in 1914 was named Alford professor of natural religion, moral philosophy, and civil polity, Harvard University; published works include: Primer of Logical Analysis for the Use of Composition Students (1881), The Religious Aspect of Philosophy (1885), The Spirit of Modern Philosophy (1892), The Conception of God (1895), The World and the Individual (1899, 1901), and The Problem of Christianity (2 vols., 1913); he died on September 14, 1916 in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Expanded Biographical/Historical Narrative
In 1927 the Regents of the University of California approved a recommendation that the main classroom building on the new Westwood campus of the University be named Royce Hall in honor of the great American scholar and philosopher, Josiah Royce. The Department of Philosophy on this campus undertook the task of assembling a Josiah Royce Memorial Collection to be placed in a designated alcove of the building, known as the Josiah Royce Alcove.
Through the generosity of Royce's family and friends, books and articles by and about Royce, originals and copies of some of his correspondence, his master's and doctor's thesis, as well as pictures, clippings and other Royce memorabilia were acquired for this collection. His own large and stately walnut bookcase was used to house the collection.
The Royce Memorial remained in Royce Hall under the care of the Philosophy Department until December, 1954. At this time, because of the program for remodeling Royce Hall, it was transferred to the University Library's Department of Special Collections.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of writings by and about Josiah Royce, copies of his correspondence, books, clippings, photographs, a typescript copy of a journal written by his mother, Sarah Eleanor Royce entitled, Across the Plains (1849), and other Royce memorabilia collected by the UCLA Department of Philosophy in memory of Royce.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Letters (Box 1).
Papers and writings (Box 2).
Writings of Josiah Royce (Boxes 3-6, 8-17).
Other books (Boxed 6-7).
Reviews of Royce's books (Boxes 16-19).
Essays in honor of Royce (Box 20).
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Royce, Josiah, 1855-1916--Archives.; Philosophers--United States--Archives.
Genres and Forms of Material
Manuscripts for publication.
Other Index Terms Related to this Collection
Royce, Sarah, 1819-1891.
Container List
- Letters and Papers
  - Biographical material. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pictures of Josiah Royce and of his mother. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    re Josiah Royce, including obituaries. A few related to his sister, Ruth Royce, Librarian of San Jose (California) State Normal School.
  - Copies of congratulations, regrets; telegrams received by Royce at the time of the anniversary dinner given to him by the American Philosophical Society.January 1916. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - War and Insurance. In the New York Times Magazine Section.July 25, 1915. (Box 1)
  - Letter.February 2, 1928, from Ruth Royce to Ralph Barton Perry. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    re Josiah Royce.
  - Letter from Eleanor R. Ingraham. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    re the armchair presented to UCLA for the Josiah Royce Alcove, Royce Hall.
  - Letters, chiefly to Ruth Royce, at the time of Josiah Royce's death. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence to Professor Hugh Miller. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    re the organization of the Royce Memorial, Royce Hall, UCLA.
  - Josiah Royce correspondence., Copies. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    re the naming of Royce Hall.
  - Royce, Sarah Eleanor. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Across the Plains., 127 leaves. Typescript (copy). (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes letter:November 1, 1929, from Ralph Barton Perry to Charles H. Rieber. Published by Yale University Press.
  - Articles and writings. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Including copies of examinations in philosophy given by him at Harvard (some are about Royce's work).
- Papers and Writings
  - The Intention of the `Prometheus Bound' of Aeschylus, Being an Investigation in the Department of Greek Theology.1875. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Thesis prepared by Royce as a candidate for the degree of Bachelor of Arts.
  - Of the Interdependence of the Principles of Knowledge; an Investigation of Elementary Epistemology... (Box 2)
    Royce's Ph.D. dissertation, Johns Hopkins University.
  - War and Insurance.September 27, 1914. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    An address by Royce delivered at Berkeley.
  - Royce's lectures on metaphysics.1915-1916. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Part 1:September 30, 1915-March 4, 1916
    Part 2:March 7, 1916-May 27, 1916.
- Writings of Josiah Royce
  - California, from the Conquest in 1846 to the Second Vigilance Committee in San Francisco--a Study of American Character. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin Company.1886., 2 copies, variant printing and binding. (Box 3)
  - The Conception of God; a Philosophical Discussion Concerning the Nature of the Divine Idea as a Demonstrable Reality, by Josiah Royce, Joseph LeConte, G.H. Howison, and Sidney Edward Mezes. New York: Macmillan Company.1897. (Box 3)
  - The Conception of Immortality. The Ingersoll Lecture, 1899. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin Company.1900. (Box 3)
  - The Feud of Oakfield Creek; a Novel of California Life. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin Company.1887., (2 copies) (Box 3)
  - Fugitive Essays. Introduction by Dr. J. Loewenberg. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.1920. (Box 3)
  - Herbert Spencer, an Estimate and Review. New York: Fox, Duffield & Company.1904. (Box 3)
  - The Hope of the Great Community. New York: Macmillan Company.1916. (Box 4)
  - Logic, by Arnold Ruge, Wilhelm Windelband, Josiah Royce, Louis Couturat, Benedetto Croce, Federigo Enriques, and Nicolaj Losskij. Translated by B. Ethel Meyer. London: Macmillan and Company.1913. (Box 4)
  - Outlines of Psychology; an Elementary Treatise with some Practical Applications. New York: Macmillan Company.1903. (Box 4)
  - The Philosophy of Loyalty. New York: Macmillan Company.1924. (Box 4)
  - The Problem of Christianity; Lectures Delivered at the Lowell Institute in Boston, and at Manchester College, Oxford. New York: Macmillan Company.1913. (Box 4)
    - vol.1: The Christian Doctrine of Life. (Box 4)
    - vol.2: The Real World and the Christian Ideal. (Box 4)
  - The Religious Aspect of Philosophy; a Critique of the Bases of Faith and Conduct. Boston: Houghton Mifflin & Company.1885. (Box 5)
  - The Sources of Religious Insight; Lectures Delivered Before Lake Forest College... New York: Charles Scribner's Sons.1923. (Box 5)
  - The Spirit of Modern Philosophy; an Essay in the Form of Lectures. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin & Company.1892. (Box 5)
  - Studies of Good and Evil; a Series of Essays Upon Problems of Philosophy and of Life. New York: D. Appleton & Company.1898. (Box 5)
  - War and Insurance; an Address Delivered Before the Philosophical Union of the University of California at its Twenty-Fifth Anniversary at Berkeley, California, August 27, 1914. New York: Macmillan Company.1914. (Box 5)
  - Willian James, and Other Essays on the Philosophy of Life. New York: Macmillan Company.1911. (Box 5)
  - Is There a Philosophy of Evolution? In the Unitarian Review (vol.32). (Box 6)
    First Paper.July.
    Second Paper.August.
  - Kühnemann, Eugen. (Box 6)
    - Schiller. Translated from the third edition of the German original by Katherine Royce; introduction by Josiah Royce. Boston and London: Ginn & Company.1912., 2 vol. (Box 6)
  - The World and the Individual; Gifford Lectures Delivered Before the University of Aberdeen. New York: Macmillan Company.1900 and 1901., 2 vol. (Box 6)
    - First series - The Four Historical Conceptions of Being. (Box 6)
    - Second series - Nature, Man, and the Moral Order. (Box 6)
  - The American College and Life. In Science (vol.29, no.741).March 12, 1909., p.401. (Box 8)
  - An American Thinker on the War. In the Hibbert Journal.October 1915., p.37. (Box 8)
  - The American University Gymnasium; its Influence on Academic Life. In Alma Mater, Aberdeen University Magazine (vol.17, no.14).February 7, 1900., p.1. 2 copies. (Box 8)
  - Atonement. In the Atlantic Monthly.March 1913., p.406. (Box 8)
  - Before and Since Kant. In the Berkeley Quarterly (vol.2, no.2).April 1881., p.134. (Box 8)
  - The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching and the case of Middlebury College. In School and Society (vol.1, no.5).January 30, 1915., p.145. (Box 8)
  - The Case of John Bunyan. In the Psychological Review (vol.1, no.1).January 1894., p.22. 2 copies. (Box 8)
  - Certitudes and Illusions. In Science (vol.3, no.62).March 6, 1896., p.354. (Box 8)
  - The Christian Doctrine of Life. In the Hibbert Journal (vol.11, no.3).April 1913., p.473. (Box 8)
  - The Concept of the Infinite. In the Hibbert Journal (vol.1, no.1).October 1902., p.21. (Box 8)
  - The Conception of God; an Address Before the Union... Berkeley, Excutive Council of the Union.1895. (Box 8)
  - The Hope of the Great Community. In the Yale Review.January 1916., p.269. 2 copies. (Box 9)
  - Hallucinations of Memory and `Telepathy.' In Mind (no.50).April 1888., p.244. (Box 9)
  - Herbert Spencer. In the International Quarterly (vol.9, no.9).June-September 1904., p.335. (Box 9)
  - Football and Ideals. In the Harvard Illustrated Magazine (vol.10, no.2).November 1908., p.40. (Box 9)
  - The Fremont Legend. A letter to the editor of the Nation (vol.52, no.1351).May 21, 1891., p.423. (Box 9)
  - George Eliot as a Religious Teacher. In The Californian (vol.3, no.16).April 1881., p.300. (Box 9)
  - Fremont. In the Atlantic Monthly (vol.66, no.396).October 1890., p.548. (Box 9)
  - The Outlook in Ethics. In International Journal of Ethics (vol.2, no.1).October 1891., p.106. (Box 9)
  - The Decay of Earnestness. In The Californian (vol.3, no.13).January 1881., p.18. (Box 9)
  - Doubting and Working. In The Californian (vol.3, no.15).March 1881., p.229. (Box 9)
  - A Case Involving Problems of Loyalty. An examination question for students in a University Extension course in ethics.1916. (Box 9)
  - The Eternal and the Practical. Reprinted from the Philosophical Review (vol.13, no.2).March 1904)., 2 copies. (Box 9)
  - The Implications of Self-Consciousness. In the New World (no.2).June 1892., p.289. (Box 10)
  - How Beliefs Are Made. Reprinted from The Californian.February 1882., 2 copies. (Box 10)
  - The Imitative Functions, and Their Place in Human Nature. In the Century Magazine.May 1894., p.137. (Box 10)
  - Immortality. In the Hibbert Journal (vol.5, no.4).July 1907., p.724. 2 copies. (Box 10)
  - Is There a Philosophy of Evolution? First paper. The Unitarian Review (vol.32, no.1).July 1889., p.1. 2 copies. (Box 10)
  - Is There a Philosophy of Evolution? Second paper. In the Unitarian Review (vol.32, no.2).August 1889., p.97. (Box 10)
  - Is there a Science of Education? Part one,Educational Review (vol.1, no.1).January 1891., p.151. (Box 10)
  - Is There a Science of Education? Part two, in Educational Review (vol.1, no.2).February 1891., p.121. (Box 10)
  - James as a Philosopher. In Science (vol.34, no.863).July 14, 1911., p.33. (Box 10)
  - John Fiske as a Thinker. In the Harvard Graduates' Magazine (vol.10, no.37).September 1901., p.23. (Box 10)
  - Joseph LeConte. In the International Monthly (vol.4, no.3).September 1901., p.324. (Box 10)
  - Kant's Doctrine of the Basis of Mathematics. In the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods. vol.2, no.8).April 13, 1905., p.197. (Box 10)
  - Kant's Relation to Modern Philosophic Progress [in the Journal of Speculative Philosophy]., 2 copies. (Box 10)
  - Natural Rights and Spinoza's Essay on Liberty. In the Berkeley Quarterly (vol.1, no.4).October 1880., p.312. (Box 11)
  - The New Psychology and the Consulting Psychologist. In the Forum (vol.26, no.1).September 1898., p.80. (Box 11)
  - A New Study of Psychology. In International Journal of Ethics (vol.1, no.2).January 1891., p.143. (Box 11)
  - The Nature of Voluntary Progress. In the Berkeley Quarterly (vol.1, no.3).July 1880., p.161. (Box 11)
  - [?????]Overland Monthly (vol.15, no.2).August 1875. (Box 11)
  - The Mechanical, the Historical and the Statistical. In Science (vol.39, no.1007).April 17, 1914., p.551. (Box 11)
  - `Mind-stuff' and Reality. In Mind (no.23).July 1881., p.365. (Box 11)
  - Mind and Reality. In Mind (no.25).January 1882., p.30. (Box 11)
  - Montgomery and Fremont: New Documents on the Bear Flag Affair. In Century Magazine (vol.41, no.5)., p.780. (Box 11)
  - Natural Law, Ethics, and Evolution. A discussion in International Journal of Ethics (vol.5, no.4).July 1895. (Box 11)
  - Light on the Seizure of California. In Century Magazine (vol.40, no.5).September 1890., p.792. (Box 11)
  - Primer of Logical Analysis for the Use of Composition Students. San Francisco: A.L. Bancroft and Company.1881., 2 copies. (Box 12)
  - Present Ideals of American University Life. In Scribner's Magazine (vol.10, no.3).September 1891., p.376. (Box 12)
  - The Problem of Truth in the Light of Recent Discussion. Paper for the International Philosophical Congress, Heidelberg.1908. (Box 12)
  - Primitive Ways of Thinking, with Special Reference to Negation and Classification. In The Open Court (vol.27, no.689).October 1913., p.577. (Box 12)
  - The Problem of Natural Religion. In the International Quarterly (vol.7, no.1).March-June 1903., p.85. (Box 12)
  - On Definitions and Debates. In the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Method (vol.9, no.4).February 15, 1912., p.85. (Box 12)
  - The Present State of the Question Regarding the First Principles of Theoretical Science. In Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society held at Philadelphia, for Promoting Useful Knowledge (vol.45, no.182).January-April, 1906., p.82. (Box 12)
  - A Plea for Provincial Independence in Education. Middlebury, Vermont.1914. (Box 12)
  - Originality and Consciousness. In the Harvard Monthly (vol.24, no.4).June 1897., p.133. (Box 12)
  - The Pacific Coast: a Psychological Study of Influence. In the International Monthly (vol.2, no.5).November 1900., p.555. 2 copies. (Box 12)
  - Pessimism and Modern Thought. In the Berkeley Quarterly (vol.2, no.4).October 1881., p.292. (Box 12)
  - Professor Royce on his Reviewer. A letter to the editor in the New Republic (vol.1, no.8).December 26, 1914., p.23. (Box 12)
  - The Practical Value of Philosophy. In the Ethical Record (vol.2).April 1889., p.9. (Box 12)
  - Nietzsche. In the Atlantic Monthly.March 1917., p.321. 2 copies. (Box 12)
  - On Certain Psychological Aspects of Moral Training. In International Journal of Ethics (vol.3, no.4).July 1893., p.28. (Box 12)
  - The Old and the New--a Lesson. In the University Chronicle (vol.5, no.2).July 1902., p.92. 2 copies. (Box 12)
  - The Sciences of the Ideal. In Science (vol.20, no.510).October 7, 1904., p.449. (Box 13)
  - Schiller's Ethical Studies. In the Journal of Speculative Philosophy (vol.12, no.4).October 1878., p.373. 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Report of the Committee on Phantasms and Presentiments.Proceedings of the American Society for Psychical Research (vol.1, no.4).March 1889., p.350. (Box 13)
  - Recent Logical Inquiries and Their Psychological Bearings. In the Psychological Review (vol.9, no.2).March 1902., p.105. (Box 13)
  - The Reality of the Temporal. Reprinted from the International Journal of Ethics (vol.20).1910., p.257. (Box 13)
  - The Psychology of Invention. In the Psychological Review (vol.5, no.2).March 1898., p.113. (Box 13)
    (Also a reprint of same)
  - Provincialism. In Putnam's Magazine (vol.7, no.2).November 1909., p.232. (Box 13)
  - Preliminary Report on Imitation. In the Psychological Review (vol.2, no.3).May 1895., p.217. (Box 13)
  - Professor Everett as a Metaphysician. In the New World (vol.9, no.36).December 1900., p.726. (Box 13)
  - Race Questions and Prejudices. In the International Journal of Ethics (vol.16, no.3).April 1906., p.265. (Box 13)
  - The Problem of Natural Religion. In the International Quarterly (vol.7, no.1).March-June 1903., p.85. (Box 13)
  - Some Psychological Problems Emphasized by Pragmatism. In the Popular Science Monthly (vol.83, no.4).October 1913., p.394. (Box 14)
  - Some Observations on the Anomalies of Self-Consciousness (1). In the Psychological Review (vol.2, no.5).September 1895., p.433. (Box 14)
  - Some Observations on the Anomalies of Self-Consciousness (2). In the Psychological Review (vol.2, no.6).November 1895., p.574. (Box 14)
  - Self-consciousness, Social Consciousness, and Nature (1). In the Philosophical Review (vol.4, no.5).September 1895., p.465. (Box 14)
  - Self-Consciousness, Social Consciousness, and Nature (2). In the Philosophical Review (vol.4, no.6).November 1895., p.577. (Box 14)
  - The Second Death. In the Atlantic Monthly (vol.3, no.2).February 1913., p.242. (Box 14)
  - Some Relations of Physical Training to the Present Problems of Moral Education in America. Boston, Boston Normal School of Gymnastics.n.d. (Box 14)
  - Two Philosophers of the Paradoxical. First paper: Hegel. In the Atlantic Monthly (vol.67, no.399).January 1891., p.45. (Box 14)
  - Two Philosophers of the Paradoxical. Second paper: Schopenhauer. In the Atlantic Monthly (vol.67, no.400).February 1891., p.161. (Box 14)
  - The Student of Philosophy. In the Harvard Monthly (vol.18, no.3).May, 1894., p.87. (Box 14)
    [Missing]
  - Wie unterschieden sich gesunde und krankhafte Geisteszustände beim Kinde? Vortrag von Josiah Royce. Translated by Chr. Ufer.Pädagogisches Magazin (vol.44).1904. (Box 14)
  - Shelley and the Revolution. In the Californian (vol.1, no.6).June 1880., p.543. (Box 14)
  - Some Relations Between Philosophy and Science in the First Half of the Nineteenth Century in Germany. In Science (vol.38, no.982).October 24, 1913., p.567. (Box 14)
  - An Extension of the Algebra of Logic. In The Journal of Philosophy, Psychology and Scientific Methods (vol.10, no.23).November 6, 1913. (Box 15)
  - George Fox as a Mystic. In the Harvard Theological Review (vol.6, no.1).January 1913., 2 copies. (Box 15)
  - Review of Mental Development in the Child and the Race: Methods and Processes, by James Mark Baldwin. In the Psychological Review (vol.3, no.2).March 1896., p.201. (Box 15)
  - What is Vital in Christianity? In the Harvard Theological Review (vol.2, no.4).October 1909., p.408. 3 copies. (Box 15)
  - What Should Be the Attitude of Teachers of Philosophy Toward Religion? In International Journal of Ethics (vol.13, no.3).April 1903., p.280. (Box 15)
  - A Word for the Times. In the Harvard Graduates' Magazine (vol.23, no.90).December 1914., p.207. (Box 15)
  - Portrait of Josiah Royce, the Philosopher. In the Outlook (vol.122, no.9).July 2, 1916., Chapman, John Jay.; p.4. (Box 16)
  - Professor Josiah Royce. In the Harvard Alumni Bulletin (vol.19, no.1).September 28, 1916., Hocking, William Ernest; p.4. (Box 16)
  - Royce's Philosophy of Religion. In Bibliotheca Sacra (vol.71, no.282).April 1914., Carr, Edwin S.; p.283. (Box 16)
  - La philosophie morale de Josiah Royce; essai sur l'idéalisme social aux Etats-Unis d'Amerique. Paris: Librairie Félix Alcan.1927., Aronson, Moses Judah (Box 16)
  - A Bibliography of the Unpublished Writings of Josiah Royce. In the Philosophical Review (vol.26, no.5).September 1917., p.578. (Box 16)
  - The Doctrine of Evolution and the Conception of God. In the American Journal of Theology (vol.19, no.4).October 1915., Kawaguchi, Ukichi; p.556. (Box 16)
  - Professor Royce and the Problem of Christianity. In the North American Review (vol.198, no.5).November 1913., Driscoll, John T.; p.640. (Box 16)
  - America's Duty Today, from the Point of View of a Hospital Doctor. In the Outlook (vol.115, no.14).April 4, 1917., Cabot, Richard C.; p.606. (Box 16)
  - The Contribution of Professor Royce to Christian Thought. In the Harvard Theological Review (vol.8, no.2).April 1915., Buckham, John Wright; p.219. 2 copies. (Box 16)
  - Review of The World and the Individual. In the Harvard Graduates' Magazine (vol.8, no.31.March 1900., Cabot, Richard C.; p.317. (Box 16)
  - Review of William James and Other Essays on the Philosophy of Life. In the International Journal of Ethics (vol.22, no.3).April 1912., p.354. (Box 16)
  - Josiah Royces Versuch einer Synthese von Pragmatismus und Objektivität. Jena, Universitäts-Buchdrukerei G. Neuenhahn.1926., Rothman, Walter (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce, 1855-1916. Reprinted from the Proceedings of the British Academy (vol.7)., Sorley, W.R. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce. In the Outlook (vol.114, no.4).September 27, 1916., p.165. (Box 17)
  - A Philosopher of Imagination. In the Nation (vol.103, no.2674).September 28, 1916., p.296. (Box 17)
  - The Philosophy of Religion. A review of The World and the Individual. In the Outlook (vol.66, no.8).October 20, 1900., p.466. (Box 17)
  - Memorials of Professor Royce. In the Harvard Alumni Bulletin (vol.19, no.14).January 4, 1917., p.261. (Box 17)
  - Some Modern Philosophy. A review of The Conception of Immortality. In the Outlook (vol.66, no.4).September 22, 1900., p.227. (Box 17)
  - Roycian Reminiscences; Letters to the Bulletin. In the Harvard Alumni Bulletin (vol.19, no.6).October 26, 1916., p.81. (Box 17)
  - The Teachings of Royce: an Estimation. In the California Alumni Fortnightly (vol.9, no.14(September 30, 1916., Loewenberg, J.; p.216. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce: Interpreter of American Problems. Reprinted from the University of California Chronicle (vol.19, no.1)., Loewenberg, J. (Box 17)
  - The Philosophy of Religion. Review of The world and the individual. In the Outlook (vol.71, no.8).June 21, 1902., p.511. (Box 17)
  - Un Pensatore Americano: Josiah Royce. Milan.1917., Ogliati, Francesco (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce: a Personal Impression. In the International Journal of Ethics (vol.27, no.2).January 1917., Mead, George H.; p.168. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce. In the Harvard Graduates' Magazine (vol.25, no.98).December 1916., Palmer, George Herbert; p.165. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce. In the Outlook (vol.121, no.3).January 15, 1919., Slattery, Charles Lewis; p.114. (Box 17)